dialectpayments.com 2007-12-15

# Dialect Payments - Privacy Policy

Privacy Policy

Dialect Payment Technologies Pty Ltd (Australian Company Number 052 950 375) ( ** _Dialect_** ) recognises its obligations - including those under the Australian Federal Privacy Act 1988 and its "National Privacy Principles" ( ** _NPP_** ) \- to keep personal information private. For further information about the NPPs see [www.privacy.gov.au](http://www.dialectpayments.com/scripts/redir.asp?link=http%3A//www.privacy.gov.au).

This privacy policy provides information about Dialect's policies relating to personal information including information on how we collect, use and disclose information via our public website.

Dialect monitors and retains information regarding traffic on its website, including the links utilised by the site's users. When Dialect receives information about you and your sessions, we may use it for research or to improve our site and the services we offer, but we will ask you prior to using your information in any other way. Unless noted otherwise, however, and with the user's consent, no personally identifiable information is retained by Dialect, although Dialect cannot make any representation as to the practices of the organisations for which links are provided.

Cookies on our public website  
To ensure Dialect's public website at [www.dialectpayments.com](http://www.dialectpayments.com/) is meeting the needs and wants of our website users, and to develop our online services, we may collect aggregated information using Cookies. Cookies will track use of the site, and may also be used to compile statistics on visits to the site in an aggregated form and log anonymous information such as:

  * the address of a user's server 
  * a user's top level domain (such as .com or .au) 
  * the date and time of a visit 
  * the pages access and downloaded 
  * the search engine used 
  * what type of browser used

When a user visits the site a Cookie may be placed on their machine. Where a user has visited us before the Cookie may be read each time the user re-visits the site.

We do not use this technology to access personal information and a user cannot be personally identified from a Cookie.

If you choose not to have your browser accept Cookies from our website, you will still be able to view the text on the screens.

Why do we collect personal information?  
Dialect or its contractors store personal information collected by or for Dialect to ensure that Dialect can maintain contact and initiate new contacts with individuals. This is for the purpose of conducting business or in the case of resumes and related employment application materials so that we may contact an individual if we are interested in interviewing the person at any time.

Dialect contact may be verbal, electronic or written. The reason for the contact may be to inform, request assistance or to maintain or initiate a new relationship.

Dialect may collect personal information from several sources including potential customers, customers, interested public and those seeking employment opportunities. 

During the course of conducting business, Dialect may collect personal information from you, via another contact in your organistation or through a third party who we believe has informed you that your details may be provided to us. Such details may include your name, position, company, address, phone number and email address. We may also collect other specific information from you relating to the services or advice you wish to obtain.

When do we use personal information?  
The personal information we collect will only be that which is necessary for the conduct of our business and initiating or maintaining our relationship with a person or their organisation.

Information gathered by us in one instance may be used in another instance unless the person expressly requested that we do not. Instances where we may use personal information include:

  * Establishing and maintaining a relationship with a client of Dialect, including the provision of newsletters, reports and other information.  

  * Answer enquiries and provide services that a person has requested of Dialect.  

  * Inform a person of upcoming events or promotions, product information and releases.

Personal information collected by Dialect is only disclosed to authorised Dialect staff or contractors so as to directly deliver our services and conduct business, including fulfilling our obligations owed to clients and under applicable laws.

How do we collect the information?  
Where practical, we will only collect information directly from you. If we collect it from another source, we will do what is reasonably possible to inform you that we have collected the information.

How do we store your personal information?  
Your information is held either in paper-based records or in electronic form in our databases or IT systems. Dialect takes reasonable steps to ensure the security of personal information is held from such risks as loss or unauthorised access, destruction, use modification or disclosure of data.

To whom will we disclose your information?  
In the course of performing its obligations, Dialect may disclose personal information to contractors providing goods or services to or on behalf of Dialect.

Contacting Dialect about Privacy and your personal information  
Dialect will take all reasonable steps to ensure that the information we hold is accurate.

To access your personal information, or if you wish to find out any further information about Dialect's Privacy Policy, please contact our Privacy Officer:

Email: [privacyofficer@dialectpayments.com  
](mailto:privacyofficer@dialectpayments.com)Fax: +61 7 3210 2566  
Telephone: +61 7 3210 2522 Mail: PO Box 10719, Adelaide Street, Brisbane QLD 4000.

Changes to this Privacy Policy  
Dialect may from time to time, amend this Privacy Policy by posting the amended versions at our website at [www.dialectpayments.com](http://www.dialectpayments.com/). We suggest that you visit regularly to keep up to date with any changes.
